# Carlo McGinley 115 Riveroaks, Claregalway, Co.Galway carlomcginley@gmail.com 0852060160

# Career Objective

I have a strong passion for all aspects of cybersecurity, with experience in working in software developments on both an academic, professional and personal level, enhancing skills I have already developed, while continuing to learn new skills.

## Education

BSc (Honours) in Computer Science & Information Technology, NUI Galway September 2016-Present

Third Year – 54.50 (2:2)

Professional Skills 77%, Programming III 40%, Networks & Data Communications II 41%, Database Systems II 55%, Organisational Innovation 68%, Software Engineering II 82%, Human Computer Interaction 40%, Programming Paradigms 62%, Games Programming 40%

Second Year – 41.00

Discrete Mathematics 35%, Software Engineering I 53%, Object-Oriented Programming 40%, Introduction to Statistical Data & Probability 40%, Database Systems I 40%, Computer Systems & organisation 35%, Networks & Data Communications I 36%, Object oriented programming: Data structures & algorithms 40%, Linear Algebra 40%, Introduction to Modelling 40%, Next Generation Technologies II 40%.

First Year – 47.17

Professional Skills I 61%, Computing Systems 42%, Algorithms & Information Systems 47%, Fundamentals of Electrical & Electronic Engineering I 53%, Programming 49%, Next Generation Technologies I 48%, Mathematics 42%, Introduction to Physics 44%.

Secondary Level Education

Pobal Scoil Gaoth Dobhair, Gweedore, Co.Donegal - 435 points Irish (H) B1, English (H) C3, Mathematics (O) B2, Geography (H) B2, Biology (H) D2, Accounting (H) C1, Business (H) A2.

# **Projects**

**Final Year Project – Call Rating System**: Developed a cloud hosted call rating engine that allows VoIP companies to bill companies in a similar manner to traditional telecommunications companies, while also allowing customers to view call history, and make payments.

**CodeCrowd**: Created and maintained a user account systems for a social networking / crowd funding hybrid website created as part of a second year group project.

**Space Invaders**: Developed a rendition of the classic video game "Space Invaders" in Java, as part of a second year project.

**Kings**: Developed a digital version of the classic Card game "Kings" in the C programming language as a personal project.

## **Achievements**

Scifest 2015, First place, Technology Category:

Received a first-place prize for my project, researching the overall effectiveness of using passwords, and the attitude 12-18 year olds took towards cybersecurity.

## Skills

#### **Fluent in Gaeilge**

Spoken as a Second Language for a number of years. Attended a Gaelscoil as part of my primary and secondary education.

#### **Teamwork**

Developed my teamworking skills through work experience and group projects.

#### Proficient in C, Javascript, Java and Python

Completed many college assignments using these languages.

#### **Experienced in Web Development using HTML and ReactJS**

Have created websites in the past, both as part of college projects, and as a secondary school project entered into the Scifest Science competition.

#### **Familiar with AWS Ecosystem**

Have utilised many components of the AWS ecosystem during the duration of my final year project.

# Work Experience

January 2020 – April 2020

Software Development Intern, Openjaw Technologies, Galway

- Developed frontend and backend software solutions as part of an agile team working to create an AI chatbot for use within the aviation industry.
- Developed unit tests for Java using the Junit framework, as well as implementing rigorous regression testing procedures.
- Participated in weekly planning meetings, and bi-weekly retrospective meetings to plan the future progression of the product, and solve problems as they appeared.

#### March 2016 - December 2019

Kitchen Porter / Commis Chef, An Chúirt hotel, Gweeedore, Co.Donegal

- Prepared Starter, Main course, and Dessert dishes.
- Ensured a high level of cleanliness was maintained throughout the kitchen and surrounding areas.
- Conferred with management regarding inventory levels.

## Referees

Michael Kenneally, Product Manager, Openjaw Technologies, Galway michael.kenneally@openjawtech.com

Lewis Connon, General Manager, An Chúirt Hotel, Gweedore, Co.Donegal lewis-connon@outlook.com